<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Techni Graphic Systems, Inc.</origin>
<pubdate>20070911</pubdate>
<title>Colleges and Universities</title>
<edition>3rd Quarter 2007</edition>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>www.nconemap.com</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>
Colleges and Universities in North Carolina

The Colleges and Universities dataset is composed of any type of Post Secondary Education such as: colleges, universities, technical schools, trade schools, business schools, satellite (branch) campuses, etc. that grant First Professional, Associate, Bachelors, Masters, or Doctoral degrees.

Text fields in this dataset have been set to all upper case to facilitate consistent database engine search results.

All diacritics (e.g. the German umlaut or the Spanish tilde) have been replaced with their closest equivalent English character to facilitate use with database systems that may not support diacritics.

The currentness of this dataset is indicated by the [CONTDATE] attribute. Based upon this attribute, the oldest record dates from 07/09/2007 and the newest record dates from 07/26/2007.
</abstract>
<purpose>
Homeland Security

Use Cases: Use cases help define and clarify requirements, and describe how the data may be used.

1) Identification of populations that may need to be evacuated in the event of an emergency.

2) Notification of groups of people who may be at risk from a contagious disease outbreak.
</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>20070709</begdate>
<enddate>20070726</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<current>ground condition</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>Unknown</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-83.965029</westbc>
<eastbc>-76.194563</eastbc>
<northbc>36.436523</northbc>
<southbc>34.038390</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>LCSH - Library of Congress subject headings (Washington, DC: LC, Cataloging Distribution Service)</themekt>
<themekey>Universities and colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Community colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Junior colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Cooking schools</themekey>
<themekey>Business schools</themekey>
<themekey>Medical colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Trade schools</themekey>
<themekey>Law schools</themekey>
<themekey>Dental schools</themekey>
<themekey>Military education</themekey>
<themekey>Sports camps</themekey>
<themekey>Conservatories of music</themekey>
<themekey>Art Study and teaching</themekey>
<themekey>Massage therapy</themekey>
<themekey>Aviation technician training course.</themekey>
<themekey>Theological seminaries</themekey>
<themekey>Executives Training of</themekey>
<themekey>Bible colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Technical institutes</themekey>
<themekey>Church and college</themekey>
<themekey>Health occupations schools</themekey>
<themekey>Islamic universities and colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Private universities and colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Public universities and colleges</themekey>
<themekey>Universities and colleges Religion</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>structure</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>LCSH - Library of Congress subject headings (Washington, DC: LC, Cataloging Distribution Service) http://authorities.loc.gov</placekt>
<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>None</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>Mike Thompson</cntper>
<cntorg>Techni Graphic Systems, Inc.</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>Director of Geospatial Datasets</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
<address>2000 Noble Drive</address>
<city>Wooster</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postal>44691</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>330-263-6222</cntvoice>
<cntfax>330-263-6294</cntfax>
<cntemail>mthompson@tgstech.com</cntemail>
<hours>8am - 5pm, Monday - Friday, Eastern Time</hours>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<secinfo>
<secsys>DOD</secsys>
<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
<sechandl>Unclassified</sechandl>
</secinfo>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>
For entities that were contacted, the name, address, city, state, and five (5) digit zip codes were verified to be correct as of the date indicated by the [CONTDATE] attribute. The existence of the entity was also verified, as well as whether or not it met the criteria for inclusion in this dataset. Four (4) digit zip code extensions were derived from USPS (United States Postal Service) data and were not verified.

ID Check: The [ID] attribute is not blank and all IDs are unique.

Coordinate Check: Coordinates are not null or zero and the x and y fields match the shape.

Basic Address Check: Physical addresses were verified to be non blank and to not be a "PO Box", "General Delivery", "Highway Contract", or "Rural Route" address.

Highway Address without Type Check: Physical addresses containing the word "Highway" or "Route" were verified to also contain a type designator such as "State", "US", or "County", if one actually exists for the highway or route. These type designators are often missing from addresses, leading to confusion if more than one "Highway" of the given number exists in an area.

Basic Name Check: Entity name is not blank, is not the same as entity city, and has a minimum of 2 characters. Name does not contain punctuation characters that can interfere with database operations, such as " (quote) and * (asterisk).

Basic Phone Check: All phone numbers (including the area code) are ten (10) numeric digits. Alphabetic characters have been converted to the corresponding numeric digit.

County FIPS to State Compare Check: The county represented by the tabular FIPS Code attribute is actually in the state specified by the state attribute.

County Name to State Compare Check: The county represented by the tabular county name attribute is actually in the state specified by the state attribute.

Phone Number Format Check: Phone numbers (including area code) were verified to be formatted as nnn-nnn-nnnn.

NPA_NXX Check: Area codes (sometimes called "Number Planning Areas", or NPA's) and central office codes (sometimes known as exchanges, or NXX's) were validated against data from the North American Number Planning Administration (NANPA). In some cases, NPA-NXX combinations did not show up in the NANPA data but were verified to work.

Zip Code Check: The zip code is five (5) or nine (9) numeric digits, is listed in the postal database, is in the same state as indicated by the entity's [STATE] attribute, and is not a PO Box only zip code.

Zip City Check: The entity's zip code and its city were verified to match according to the USPS Address Information System (AIS).

NAICS Code Check: Verifies the NAICS field is not blank, the NAICS Code is one of the accepted codes for this layer, and that certain key words in the entity name do not conflict with the NAICS Code.

Collocation Check: Entities with different addresses must not share the exact same geospatial location.

Geographic Spell Check: Words that appear in the entity name were checked against a standard English word list (and Spanish word list for entities in Puerto Rico). Words not appearing in these standard word lists were then checked against names appearing in the Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) of geographic features that are located within 25 miles of the entity. Proper names were manually reviewed for correct spelling.
</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>See "Attribute_Accuracy_Report". Many of the checks described in that section check for both attribute accuracy and logical consistency.</logic>
<complete>
This dataset consists of Colleges and Universities in North Carolina.

Secondary education facilities, Administrative offices, or Post Secondary Education facilities that are non degree granting schools are intended to be excluded from this dataset, but a few may be included.
</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>The geographic location of contacted entities was verified to be correct relative to the street data and version indicated by the [ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION] attributes. The horizontal accuracy is indicated by the [GEOPREC] attribute.  A value of "BLOCKFACE" indicates the entity was geocoded on the correct block and correct side of the street.  A value of "ONENTITY" indicates that the location is on the entity's facility as determined by USGS DOQQ imagery and that it is on the correct block and correct side of the street.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>State Partners and TGS research</origin>
<pubdate>2007</pubdate>
<title>Colleges and Universities</title>
<edition>Unspecified</edition>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>Online</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2007</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>Coll_Univ</srccitea>
<srccontr>This was used as a source for Colleges and Universities.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>NAVTEQ</origin>
<pubdate>2006</pubdate>
<title>NAVSTREETS</title>
<edition>2006.4</edition>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2006</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NAVTEQ_Streets_2006_Q4</srccitea>
<srccontr>NAVTEQ streets were used as a reference in the automatic geocoding and manual geolocating of entities during processing.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>
TGS Processing
&gt;
&gt;1) Verified name, physical address, and phone numbers by contacting the entity or an authority responsible for the entity.
&gt;
&gt;2) Determined or verified the geospatial location for the entity through contact with entity or authority responsible for entity. Entities were asked to describe their geospatial location relative to land marks visible in ortho imagery.
&gt;
&gt;3) All text fields were set to upper case.
&gt;
&gt;4) Leading and trailing spaces were trimmed from all text fields. These spaces can interfere with some database queries.
&gt;
&gt;5) Non printable and diacritic characters were removed from all text fields. These values have been found to prevent data from being loaded into some spatial database engines.
</procdesc>
<srcused>Coll_Univ</srcused>
<srcused>NAVTEQ_Streets_2006_Q4</srcused>
<procdate>20070911</procdate>
<srcprod>North Carolina_Coll_Univ_2007</srcprod>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>Nicole Hackworth</cntper>
<cntorg>Techni Graphic Systems, Inc.</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
<address>2000 Noble Drive</address>
<city>Wooster</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postal>44691</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>330-263-6222</cntvoice>
<cntemail>nhackworth@tgstech.com</cntemail>
<hours>8am - 5pm, Monday - Friday, Eastern Time</hours>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>130</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<geograph>
<latres>0.000001</latres>
<longres>0.000001</longres>
<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
</geograph>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>Colleges and Universities in North Carolina</enttypl>
<enttypd>The Colleges and Universities dataset is composed of any type of Post Secondary Education such as: colleges, universities, technical schools, trade schools, business schools, satellite (branch) campuses, etc. that grant First Professional, Associate, Bachelors, Masters, or Doctoral degrees.</enttypd>
<enttypds>TGS</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Unique identifier for feature.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>METLNKID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Link to Metadata.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FEATTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Geometry type of feature.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>POINT</edomv>
<edomvd>Feature is represented by point.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SECCLASS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Security classification of feature.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>UNCLASSIFIED</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity is unclassified.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of entity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Three (3) digit telephone area code for entity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Valid area codes without punctuation. Only numeric digits are used. A list of valid area codes can be found at http://www.nanpa.com</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PHONE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Seven (7) digit telephone number for entity formatted as nnn-nnnn. All alphabetic characters have been translated to the corresponding numeric digit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Phone numbers formatted as nnn-nnnn. Only numeric digits are used. The first three (3) digits (the exchange) must form a valid combination with the area code. A list of valid area code and exchange combinations can be obtained from http://www.nanpa.com</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ADDRESS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Physical street address for entity. "PO Box", "General Delivery", "Rural Route", and "Highway Contract" addresses are not considered physical addresses and should not appear in this attribute. Some areas do not have regular city style addressing so entities in those areas may not have a street number. In such cases, the name of the road they are located on is listed in this attribute.  Some rural areas may not have named roads.  In these rare cases, this attribute will be blank.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ADDRESS2</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Location within physical address, e.g., floor, suite, building.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>CITY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>
The name of the city associated with the entity's physical address. For physical addresses that the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) delivers to, this should be a "city" acceptable to the USPS as defined in their Address Information System (AIS). Sometimes the USPS does not deliver mail to a physical address but recognizes the location (i.e., they list the location as "undeliverable"). The cities associated with these locations are acceptable. In some cases, the USPS does not recognize individual physical addresses in a city, rather, they list the city as having "General Delivery". In these cases, the city and associated zip code are acceptable (the entity's [ADDRESS] attribute will contain a street address, not "general delivery"). The entity may not actually be located within the city limits of the "city" specified in its city field. Instead, it may actually be located within the city limits of another city. In some cases, the "city" that appears in this attribute may not even be a city in an administrative sense, but it is still an acceptable "city" to the USPS. An example of this is "Notre Dame, IN". There is no city in Indiana called "Notre Dame", but this is considered an acceptable city by the USPS for any delivery going to the University of Notre Dame which is actually located in the city of South Bend. "Notre Dame", like most USPS cities, is an easily recognized place, and it gives the user of the data a good general idea of where the entity is located (if the entity is located in a small municipality, the USPS "city" may be more recognizable than the name of the municipality), and it would be part of the address one would use to send a shipment to the entity's location. Using the USPS acceptable "city" also allows someone to do a logical consistency check between the zip code and the city by using the USPS AIS.

Sometimes an entity may report a city that is not accepted by the USPS, and although TGS has tried to replace those cities with an acceptable alternative, some of them may remain in this dataset.
</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Two (2) character abbreviation for state associated with the entity's physical address. In almost all cases this is the same as the state where the entity has been depicted geospatially. However, there are cases, particularly where an entity is part of a larger facility that cuts across state lines, where the entity's location may be depicted in a state other than the one indicated in this attribute. Also, the state in which an entity appears to be located may change depending on the scale of the state boundary theme being used.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>Official USPS Abbreviations - State Abbreviations</codesetn>
<codesets>United States Postal Service http://www.usps.com/ncsc/lookups/usps_abbreviations.html</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ZIP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Five (5) digit USPS zip code for entity's physical location.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>USPS Address Information System - Domain is further restricted by only allowing physical (non PO Box) zip codes.</codesetn>
<codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ZIPP4</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Four (4) digit USPS zip code extension. This attribute was automatically assigned using the entity's physical address and USPS address information system (AIS) data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>USPS Address Information System (AIS) - ZIP9</codesetn>
<codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>County name where entity is located.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</codesetn>
<codesets>US Department of the Interior - US Geologic Survey</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FIPS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Five (5) digit FIPS (Federal Information Processing Standards) Code for the County where entity is located. The first two (2) digits represent the state and the last three (3) digits identify the county within the state.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards Publications - Counties and Equivalent Entities of the U.S., Its Possessions, and Associated Areas</codesetn>
<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) http://www.itl.nist.gov/fipspubs/co-codes/states.txt</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DIRECTIONS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Directions to entity location, or description of the entity's location.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EMERGTITLE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Title of person or name of office for emergency point of contact.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EMERGPHONE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Ten (10) digit telephone number of emergency point of contact formatted as nnn-nnn-nnnn. All alphabetic characters have been translated to the corresponding numeric digit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Phone numbers, including area code, formatted as nnn-nnn-nnnn. A list of valid area code and exchange combinations can be found at http://www.nanpa.com</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EMERGEXT</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Telephone extension for emergency point of contact.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>CONTDATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Date entity was contacted by TGS.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>CONTHOW</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Method by which entity was contacted.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PHONE</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was contacted by phone.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FAX</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was contacted by fax.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MAIL</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was contacted by mail.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>EMAIL</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was contacted by email.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>WEB</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity information was gathered and/or verified by official entity website as a last resort.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ALT REF</edomv>
<edomvd>Geospatial reference information obtained from local authorities, e.g., downloadable parcel maps, 911 streets.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GEODATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Date entity was geocoded by TGS.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GEOHOW</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Method by which entity was geocoded.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>AUTO</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was automatically geocoded.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MANUAL</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was manually geocoded.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ADJUSTED</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was shifted by TGS to an updated set of NAVTEQ streets. This only applies if the entity was manually geocoded by TGS to a previous version of NAVTEQ streets.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PROVIDED</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was geocoded using coordinates provided by the state.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NAICSCODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>NAICS (North American Industry Classification System) Code for entity. NAICS codes (and NAICS Descriptions) have been assigned based upon the entity's primary function, regardless of if that is the function that qualified it to be included in this dataset.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>North American Industry Classification System (NAICS 2002)</codesetn>
<codesets>US Census Bureau - http://www.census.gov/epcd/www/naics.html</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NAICSDESCR</attrlabl>
<attrdef>
NAICS (North American Industry Classification System) Description for entity. The "Index Entries" that appear on the NAICS webpage (http://www.census.gov/epcd/www/naics.html) are being used to populate this attribute as opposed to the "NAICS Title". While there is a one to one correspondence between NAICS Codes and "NAICS Titles", there is a one to many relationship between NAICS Codes and the "Index Entries". By using the "Index Entries", we have placed the entities that make up this layer into more specific categories; however, the user of this data should be aware that this was not the intended purpose of these "Index Entries". The "Index Entries" were intended as a way to search the NAICS database and as a way of enumerating ways in which establishments falling under the given NAICS Code may be named. Thus, there are often two or more "Index Entries" that are synonyms, for example: "Prisons" and "Penitentiaries". In cases like this, we have standardized on one "Index Entry".

NAICS Descriptions (and NAICS Codes) have been assigned based upon the entity's primary function, regardless of the function that qualified it to be included in this dataset.
</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ACADEMIES, COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY</edomv>
<edomvd>ACADEMIES, COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>AVIATION SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>AVIATION SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on aviation.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BUSINESS COLLEGES OR SCHOOLS OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES</edomv>
<edomvd>BUSINESS COLLEGES OR SCHOOLS OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant baccalaureate or graduate degrees on business.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>COLLEGES (EXCEPT JUNIOR COLLEGES)</edomv>
<edomvd>COLLEGES (EXCEPT JUNIOR COLLEGES)- [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning  in the liberal arts and/or sciences based to educate and grant bachelor degrees.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>COMMUNITY COLLEGES</edomv>
<edomvd>COMMUNITY COLLEGES - [NAICS Code 611210]: Entities that are a nonresidential institution of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees below the baccalaureate level, and are often funded by the government.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>COMPUTER TRAINING (EXCEPT REPAIR)</edomv>
<edomvd>COMPUTER TRAINING (EXCEPT REPAIR) - [NAICS Code 611420]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on computers such as Business Information Systems, Networking &amp; Technical Management.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>COURT REPORTING SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>COURT REPORTING SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611410]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on court reporting.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>CULINARY ARTS SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>CULINARY ARTS SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611519]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on culinary arts.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FINE ARTS SCHOOLS (EXCEPT ACADEMIC)</edomv>
<edomvd>FINE ARTS SCHOOLS (EXCEPT ACADEMIC) - [NAICS Code 611610]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on fine arts.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>GOLF INSTRUCTION, CAMPS, OR SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>GOLF INSTRUCTION, CAMPS, OR SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611620]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on athletic activities.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT SCHOOLS OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES</edomv>
<edomvd>HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT SCHOOLS OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant baccalaureate or graduate degrees on hospitality management.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>JUNIOR COLLEGES</edomv>
<edomvd>JUNIOR COLLEGES - [NAICS Code 611210]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and granting a certificate of title instead of a degree for first two years of a four-year undergraduate course.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>LAW SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>LAW SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant degrees on law.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MANAGEMENT DEVELOPMENT TRAINING</edomv>
<edomvd>MANAGEMENT DEVELOPMENT TRAINING - [NAICS Code 611430]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant job-specific certification on management development.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MASSAGE THERAPIST INSTRUCTION</edomv>
<edomvd>MASSAGE THERAPIST INSTRUCTION - [NAICS Code 611519]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant job-specific certification in massage therapy.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MECHANIC'S SCHOOLS (EXCEPT APPRENTICESHIP)</edomv>
<edomvd>MECHANIC'S SCHOOLS (EXCEPT APPRENTICESHIP) - [NAICS Code 611519]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant job-specific certification on mechanics such as making, using, or repairing machines, vehicles, and tools.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MEDICAL SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>MEDICAL SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and grant medical degrees.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MILITARY ACADEMIES, COLLEGE LEVEL</edomv>
<edomvd>MILITARY ACADEMIES, COLLEGE LEVEL - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and train men and women for military careers.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MUSIC SCHOOLS (EXCEPT ACADEMIC)</edomv>
<edomvd>MUSIC SCHOOLS (EXCEPT ACADEMIC) - [NAICS Code 611610]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate specialize and study music.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PHOTOGRAPHY SCHOOLS, ART</edomv>
<edomvd>PHOTOGRAPHY SCHOOLS, ART - [NAICS Code 611610]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to educate and offering instruction of taking and printing photographs or making movies.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PROFESSIONAL SCHOOLS (E.G., BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, DENTAL, LAW, MEDICAL)</edomv>
<edomvd>PROFESSIONAL SCHOOLS (E.G., BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, DENTAL, LAW, MEDICAL) - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning based to offer courses and seminars for management and professional development.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>TECHNICAL AND TRADE SCHOOLS</edomv>
<edomvd>TECHNICAL AND TRADE SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 61151]: Entities that are institutions offering job or career vocational or technical courses of higher learning based to educate and grant job-specific certification.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>THEOLOGICAL SEMINARIES OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES</edomv>
<edomvd>THEOLOGICAL SEMINARIES OFFERING BACCALAUREATE OR GRADUATE DEGREES - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of higher learning relating to theology or to specialized religious study based to educate and grant baccalaureate or graduate degrees.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>UNIVERSITIES</edomv>
<edomvd>UNIVERSITIES - [NAICS Code 611310]: Entities that are institutions of the highest level of education including a graduate school and/or professional schools that awards undergraduate bachelor, master, and/or doctorate degrees.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GEOLINKID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Link ID for the street segment to which the entity was geocoded. Refer to the [ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION] attributes for the street vendor and version that was used to geocode the entity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Text</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>X</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Longitude in WGS 84 Decimal Degrees.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>-180</rdommin>
<rdommax>180</rdommax>
<attrunit>WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrunit>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Y</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Latitude in WGS 84 Decimal Degrees.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>-90</rdommin>
<rdommax>90</rdommax>
<attrunit>WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrunit>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ST_VENDOR</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Indicates name of vendor providing original street data used for geocoding.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NAVTEQ</edomv>
<edomvd>NAVTEQ streets were used for geocoding.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>TGS</edomv>
<edomvd>TGS drew in a new street segment that does not exist in the file supplied by NAVTEQ.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was geocoded using coordinates provided by the state; therefore, the street vendor is unknown.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ST_VERSION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Indicates the year and quarter of streets used for geocoding.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2006Q4</edomv>
<edomvd>2006Q4 NAVTEQ Street Data used for geocoding.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity was geocoded using coordinates provided by the state; therefore, the street version is unknown.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GEOPREC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Geocoding precision.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BLOCKFACE</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity is geocoded to correct block and correct side of street per street data indicated by [ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION].</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ONENTITY</edomv>
<edomvd>Entity is geocoded on entity rooftop per aerial imagery (in most cases USGS DOQQs).</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PHONELOC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Indicates whether the phone number in the phone field rings to the actual location of the entity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>YES</edomv>
<edomvd>Phone number rings to the actual entity location.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NO</edomv>
<edomvd>Phone number does not ring to the actual entity location. It might ring to an administrative office or central location.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
<edomvd>Unknown - It is not known if the entity's phone number rings to the entity's location.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>QC_QA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Organization that performed Quality Control/Quality Assurance on the record.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>TGS</edomv>
<edomvd>TGS has performed Quality Control/Quality Assurance on the entity record after 01/01/2005.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
<edomvd>The record is not TGS added or has not had Quality Control/Quality Assurance performed by TGS, or Quality Control/Quality Assurance was performed prior to 01/01/2005.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DEGREE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>
Highest level of degree offered by the institution.

The values in this attribute have not been validated or checked by TGS.
</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is an Associate's Degree.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>AT LEAST 2, BUT LESS THAN 4 ACADEMIC YRS</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is at least 2, but less than 4 academic yrs.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>AWARD OF LESS THAN ONE ACADEMIC YEAR</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is an award of less than one academic year.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BACHELOR'S DEGREE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is a Bachelor's Degree.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>DOCTOR'S DEGREE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is a Doctor's Degree.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MASTER'S DEGREE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is a Master's Degree.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NOT APPLICABLE, FIRST-PROFESSIONAL ONLY</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is not applicable, First-Professional Only.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>POST-MASTER'S CERTIFICATE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is a Post-Master's Certificate.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>POST BACCALAUREATE CERTIFICATE</edomv>
<edomvd>Indicates the facility highest level of degree offered is a Postbaccalaureate Certificate.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
<edomvd>Unknown or not provided.</edomvd>
<edomvds>TGS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ENROLL</attrlabl>
<attrdef>
Indicates the total enrollment for the facility.

The values that this attribute have not been validated or checked by TGS.
</attrdef>
<attrdefs>TGS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Number</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>NC Center for Geographic Information and Analysis</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Database Administration</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Physical</addrtype>
<address>333 E. Six Forks Rd.</address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>North Carolina</state>
<postal>27609</postal>
<country>U.S.A.</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Mailing</addrtype>
<address>20322 Mail Service Center</address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>North Carolina</state>
<postal>27699</postal>
<country>U.S.A.</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>919-754-6580</cntvoice>
<cntfax>919-715-8551</cntfax>
<cntemail>dataq@its.nc.gov</cntemail>
<hours>8:30AM - 5:30PM</hours>
<cntinst>Phone and electronic mail preferred</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<distliab>
NCCGIA is charged with the development and maintenance
of NC OneMap and, in cooperation with other mapping
organizations, is committed to offering its users accurate,
useful, and current information. Although
every effort has been made to ensure the accuracy of
information, errors and conditions originating from
physical sources used to develop this dataset may be
reflected in the data supplied. The user must be
aware of possible conditions and bear responsibility for
the appropriate use of the information with respect to
possible errors, original map scale, collection methodology,
currency of data, and other conditions specific to certain
data. NCCGIA does not support secondary distribution of
this dataset without its current, compliant metadata record. The
use of trade names or commercial products does not constitute their
endorsement by NCCGIA or North Carolina State Government.
</distliab>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>ESRI shapefile (*.shp)</formname>
</digtinfo>
<digtopt>
<onlinopt>
<computer>
<networka>
<networkr>ftp://ftp.nconemap.com/outgoing/vector/colluniv.zip</networkr>
</networka>
</computer>
</onlinopt>
</digtopt>
</digform>
<fees>None. Download from www.nconemap.com is free of charge.</fees>
</stdorder>
<custom>Data can be customized on a cost-recovery basis. Contact dataq@its.nc.gov or 919-754-6580 for more information.</custom>
<techpreq>This data is provided as an ESRI shapefile. Other formats are available on a cost-recovery basis - contact dataq@its.nc.gov or 919-754-6580 for more information. Format compatibility is the user's responsibility.</techpreq>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20110610</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>North Carolina Center for Geographic Information and Analysis</cntorg>
<cntper>David Giordano</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Database Administration</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Physical</addrtype>
<address>333 E. Six Forks Rd.</address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>North Carolina</state>
<postal>27609</postal>
<country>U.S.A.</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Mailing</addrtype>
<address>20322 Mail Service Center</address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>North Carolina</state>
<postal>27699</postal>
<country>U.S.A.</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>919-754-6580</cntvoice>
<cntfax>919-715-8551</cntfax>
<cntemail>dataq@its.nc.gov</cntemail>
<hours>8am to 5pm</hours>
<cntinst>Phone and electronic mail preferred</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
<metac>None</metac>
<metuc>This metadata file is to accompany the dataset. NCCGIA does not support secondary distribution of this dataset without its current, compliant metadata record. If the dataset described in this metadata record was received from anyone besides NCCGIA, this metadata and the dataset it describes may contain discrepancies.</metuc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
