<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Coastal Services Center (CSC)</origin>
<pubdate>20130904</pubdate>
<title>C-CAP Southeast Region 2010-Era Land Cover</title>
<geoform>Map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Charleston SC</pubplace>
<publish>NOAA's Ocean Service, Coastal Services Center (CSC)</publish>
</pubinfo>
<othercit>
This classification is based on Landsat 5 TM scenes
p014r035   08/09/2009 and 04/06/2010
p014r036   04/06/2010 and 10/15/2010
p015r035   04/29/2010 and 09/20/2010
p015r036   01/23/2010 and 04/13/2010
p015r037   02/08/2010 and 07/02/2010
p016r035   07/25/2010 and 10/29/2010
p016r036   06/23/2010 and 10/29/2010
p016r037   03/19/2010 and 06/07/2010
p016r038   07/09/2010 and 10/13/2010
p017r036   10/01/2009 and 04/11/2010
p017r037   09/02/2010 and 12/23/2010
p017r038   02/03/2009 and 04/24/2009
p017r039   06/14/2010 and 01/08/2011
p018r037   04/02/2010 and 06/21/2010
p018r038   05/20/2010 and 12/14/2010
p018r039   04/02/2010 and 07/23/2010
p019r037   09/29/2009 and 11/16/2009
p019r038   04/09/2010 and 11/19/2010
p019r039   02/20/2010 and 04/09/2010
</othercit>
<onlink>http://www.csc.noaa.gov/landcover</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This is a final classification. It is ready for distribution. This data set is the 2010-era classification of U.S. Southeast region. This data set utilized 38 full or partial Landsat scenes which were analyzed according to the Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP) protocol to determine land cover.</abstract>
<purpose>To improve the understanding of coastal uplands and wetlands, and their linkages with the distribution, abundance, and health of living marine resources.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>20090203</begdate>
<enddate>20110108</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<current>Date of the Landsat scenes</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>5 years</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-86.505862</westbc>
<eastbc>-74.891378</eastbc>
<northbc>38.134036</northbc>
<southbc>29.405308</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Remotely Sensed Imagery/Photos</themekey>
<themekey>Land Cover Analysis</themekey>
<themekey>Change Detection Analysis</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>None</placekt>
<placekey>Coastal Zone</placekey>
<placekey>U.S. Southeast Region</placekey>
<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
<placekey>South Carolina</placekey>
<placekey>Georgia</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None, except for a possible fee.</accconst>
<useconst>Data set is not for use in litigation. While efforts have been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the state of the art, NOAA, cannot assume liability for any damages, or misrepresentations, caused by any inaccuracies in the data, or as a result of the data to be used on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</useconst>
<native>ERDAS Imagine 2011 on Microsoft Windows 7 Professional x64 Version 2009 Service Pack 1</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>
According to an accuracy assessment performed by the NOAA Coastal Service Center for Southeast, the overall accuracy for the region 2010 classification is 81.8% and 0.80 Kappa.

Each class accuracy is as follows: (Producer’s Accuracy/User’s Accuracy)
0 Background (N/A)
1 Unclassified (Cloud, Shadow, etc)(N/A)
2 High Intensity Developed (96% / 84%)
3 Medium Intensity Developed (77% / 89%)
4 Low Intensity Developed (91% / 95%)
5 Open Spaces Developed (95% / 82%)
6 Cultivated Land (86% / 84%)
7 Pasture/Hay (57% / 91%)
8 Grassland (78% / 81%)
9 Deciduous Forest (85% / 82%)
10 Evergreen Forest (92% / 76%)
11 Mixed Forest (75% / 58%)
12 Scrub/Shrub (68% / 83%)
13 Palustrine Forested Wetland (93% / 86%)
14 Palustrine Scrub/Shrub Wetland (78% / 79%)
15 Palustrine Emergent Wetland (76% / 79%)
16 Estuarine Forested Wetland (NA / NA)
17 Estuarine Scrub/Shrub Wetland (44% / 100%)
18 Estuarine Emergent Wetland (96% / NA)
19 Unconsolidated Shore (46% / 79%)
20 Bare Land (71% / 88%)
21 Water (95% / 80%)
22 Palustrine Aquatic Bed (100% / 100%)
23 Estuarine Aquatic Bed (NA / NA)

A stratified sampling scheme was developed specifically for this land cover and change product.  Three strata were chosen for sampling; mapped change areas, near current change (2006-2010) and previous change (1996-2001 and 2001-2006) areas, and the remaining area.  The mapped change area was chosen to ensure statements could be made about change mapping accuracy.  The near change stratum was chosen under the assumption that change tends to be spatially autocorrelated, and current change will often occur near previous change.  Locations in this stratum may identify potential missed change as well as provide locations for wall-to-wall accuracy.  The final stratum locations may identify missed change and provide locations for wall-to-wall accuracy.  The first stratum was equal in size to the amount of 2006-2010 change; the remaining area was split between the other two strata.  ERDAS Imagine was used to perform a stratified random sample per stratum.  Three hundred sample units were placed per stratum, with the following criteria: minimum 6 of 9 pixels (3x3 window around location) had to have the same land cover call and minimum sample size of 10 per class (not always met).
Each sample unit was photointerpreted by two reviewers using current, and previous, Landsat data, and available ancillary data, including but not limited to, Google Earth, Bing Maps, NWI, and SSURGO soils.  The reviewer would label the point the dominant land cover for a 3x3 pixel window centered on the location, a fuzzy land cover call if needed, and identify if the point was change.  For points where the two reviewers were in disagreement, discussions would be held to come to an agreement.
The current land cover and change status for the sample units were extracted from the land cover from a 3x3 window around the sample location for analyses.  The land cover and change identifies were then compared to the reviewers primary and fuzzy (or change) call.  To be deemed a “correct” call, 6 of the 9 land cover pixels had to match either the primary or fuzzy land cover call (or change)
Post-Processing Steps: None

Known Problems: None

Spatial Filters: None
</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>Tests for logical consistency indicate that all row and column positions in the selected latitude/longitude window contain data. Conversion and integration with vector files indicates that all positions are consistent with earth coordinates covering the same area. Attribute files are logically consistent.</logic>
<complete>Data do not exist for all classes. There are no pixels representing class 23 (Estuarine Aquatic Bed), class 24 (Tundra), and class 25 (Snow/Ice). Class 1 (Unclassified) is intentionally left blank. All pixels have been classified. The NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA National Marine Fisheries Service Report 123, discusses the interagency effort to develop the land cover classification scheme and defines all categories.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Landsat scenes were geo-referenced by Eros Data Center. Spatial accuracy assessed by Photo Science, Inc is found to be to within 2 pixels accuracy.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
<vertacc>
<vertaccr>No vertical reference for this data.</vertaccr>
</vertacc>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Photo Science, Inc.</origin>
<pubdate>20130904</pubdate>
<title>C-CAP Southeast 2010-Era Land Cover Classification</title>
<geoform>map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Charleston SC</pubplace>
<publish>NOAA Coastal Services Center</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>http://www.csc.noaa.gov/landcover</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>DVD/CD-ROM</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>20090203</begdate>
<enddate>20110108</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>Date of the Landsat scenes</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NOAA CSC</srccitea>
<srccontr>NOAA CSC</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>
This dataset was created by Photo Science, Inc. This classification is based on Landsat TM imagery from the MRLC database. The study area includes all or portions of zones 55, 58, and 60 - U.S. Southeast Region.

Pre-processing steps:
Each Landsat TM scene was geo-referenced by USGS (United States Geological Survey) EROS Data Center. The data were geo-referenced to Albers Conical Equal Area, with a spheroid of GRS 1980, and Datum of WGS84. The data units are in meters. At-satellite reflectance was performed on each scene and the tasseled cap transformation applied. All of the image data used were Landsat TM 5. Photo Science, Inc. staff verified the scenes for spatial accuracy to within 2 pixels. Image change detection and classification were performed per Landsat path/row.

Change Detection:
Areas of change between 2006 and 2011 were determined by primarily using a modification of the USGS Multi-Integrated Index Change Analysis (MIICA) method, though image subtraction using individual Landsat bands, band ratios, or Tasseled Cap bands was occasionally used. The change layer is a slight over-estimation of change to ensure that as much change as detectable was included.

Classification:
The classification of the change areas was a mixture of automated and manual approaches. The change areas were removed from the 2006 classification. The areas with no change between 2006 and 2010 were used as training for a Classification And Regression Tree (CART) analysis of the changed areas. Modelling and hand-editing were used to further refine the CART output and create a final classification.  The classified change areas were overlaid on the 2006 C-CAP product to create a 2010 C-CAP classification. Attributes for this product are as follows:

0 Background
1 Unclassified (Cloud, Shadow, etc)
2 High Intensity Developed
3 Medium Intensity Developed
4 Low Intensity Developed
5 Open Space Developed
6 Cultivated Land
7 Pasture/Hay
8 Grassland
9 Deciduous Forest
10 Evergreen Forest
11 Mixed Forest
12 Scrub/Shrub
13 Palustrine Forested Wetland
14 Palustrine Scrub/Shrub Wetland
15 Palustrine Emergent Wetland
16 Estuarine Forested Wetland
17 Estuarine Scrub/Shrub Wetland
18 Estuarine Emergent Wetland
19 Unconsolidated Shore
20 Bare Land
21 Water
22 Palustrine Aquatic Bed
23 Estuarine Aquatic Bed
24 Tundra
25 Snow/Ice

Post-processing steps:
The QA process during the creation the 2010 land cover identified some errors in the previous dates of land cover that needed to be addressed to make a more accurate product.  Editing was performed on all dates of land cover to address site specific and region wide issues.  While the changes may not be large in area and/or be directly reflected in the accuracy assessment, we feel the products more accurately reflect the land cover for the time period.
</procdesc>
<procdate>20130904</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>CRS (Coastal Remote Sensing) Program Manager</cntper>
<cntorg>NOAA Coastal Services Center Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP)</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>CRS Program Manager</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>2234 S. Hobson Ave.</address>
<city>Charleston</city>
<state>SC</state>
<postal>29405</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>843-740-1210</cntvoice>
<cntfax>843-740-1224</cntfax>
<cntemail>clearinghouse@noaa.gov</cntemail>
<hours>8:00 am to 5:00 p.m. EST. M-F</hours>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Classification</procdesc>
<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>NOAA Coastal Services Center Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP)</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>CRS Program Manager</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>2234 S. Hobson Ave.</address>
<city>Charleston</city>
<state>SC</state>
<postal>29405</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>843-740-1210</cntvoice>
<cntfax>843-740-1224</cntfax>
<cntemail>csc@noaa.gov</cntemail>
<hours>Monday to Friday, 8 a.m. to 5 p.m., Eastern Standard Time</hours>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Raster</direct>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<planar>
<mapproj>
<mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
<albers>
<stdparll>29.5</stdparll>
<stdparll>45.5</stdparll>
<longcm>96 West</longcm>
<latprjo>23 North</latprjo>
<feast>0.00000</feast>
<fnorth>0.00000</fnorth>
</albers>
</mapproj>
<planci>
<plance>Row and column</plance>
<coordrep>
<absres>30 meter</absres>
<ordres>30 meter</ordres>
</coordrep>
<plandu>Meters</plandu>
</planci>
</planar>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>North American Datum 1983</horizdn>
<ellips>GRS80</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
<denflat>298.257</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>U.S. Southeast Region</enttypl>
<enttypd>C-CAP Southeast as delineated by NOAA using scene boundaries, hydrological units, and county boundaries</enttypd>
<enttypds>unknown</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Landcover Classification</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Landcover Classification as determined by NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS (National Marine Fisheries Service) 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1 Unclassified</edomv>
<edomvd>This class contains no data due to cloud conditions or data voids.</edomvd>
<edomvds>N/A</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2 High Intensity Developed</edomv>
<edomvd>Contains little or no vegetation. This subclass includes heavily built-up urban centers as well as large constructed surfaces in suburban and rural areas.  Large buildings (such as multiple family housing, hangars, and large barns), interstate highways, and runways typically fall into this subclass.  Impervious surfaces account for 80-100 percent of the total cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3 Medium Intensity Developed</edomv>
<edomvd>Contains substantial amounts of constructed surface mixed with substantial amounts of vegetated surface. Small buildings (such as single family housing, farm outbuildings, and large sheds), typically fall into this subclass. Impervious surfaces account for 50-79 percent of the total cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4 Low Intensity Developed</edomv>
<edomvd>Contains constructed surface mixed with vegetated surface. This class includes features seen class 3, with the addition of streets and roads with associated trees and grasses. Impervious surfaces account for 21-49 percent of the total cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5 Developed Open Space</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes areas with a mixture of some constructed materials, but mostly vegetation in the form of lawn grasses. This subclass includes parks, lawns, athletic fields, golf courses, and natural grasses occurring around airports and industrial sites. Impervious surfaces account for less than 20 percent of total cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6 Cultivated Land</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes herbaceous (cropland) and woody (e.g., orchards, nurseries, and vineyards) cultivated lands.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7 Pasture/Hay</edomv>
<edomvd>Characterized by grasses, legumes or grass-legume mixtures planted for livestock grazing or the production of seed or hay crops.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>8 Grassland</edomv>
<edomvd>Dominated by naturally occurring grasses and non-grasses (forbs) that are not fertilized, cut, tilled, or planted regularly.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>9 Deciduous Forest</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes areas dominated by single stemmed, woody vegetation unbranched 0.6 to 1 meter above the ground and having a height greater than 5 meters and cover more than 20% of land area. More than 75 percent of the tree species shed foliage simultaneous in response to seasonal change.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>10 Evergreen Forest</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes areas in which more than 67 percent of the trees remain green throughout the year. Both coniferous and broad-leaved evergreens are included in this category.  Trees must be taller than 5 meters and more than 20% of the land cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>11 Mixed Forest</edomv>
<edomvd>Contains all forested areas in which both evergreen and deciduous trees are growing and neither predominate. Trees must be taller than 5 meters and more than 20% of the land cover.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>12 Scrub/Shrub</edomv>
<edomvd>Areas dominated by woody vegetation less than 5 meters in height. This class includes true shrubs,young trees, and trees or shrubs that are small or stunted because of environmental conditions. Includes both evergreen and deciduous scrub.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>13 Palustrine Forested Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all non-tidal wetlands dominated by woody vegetation greater than or equal to 5 meters in height, and all such wetlands that occur in tidal areas in which salinity due to ocean-derived salts is below 0.5 parts per thousand (ppt).</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>14 Palustrine Scrub/Shrub Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all non-tidal wetlands dominated by woody vegetation less than or equal to 5 meters in height, and all such wetlands that occur in tidal areas in which salinity due to ocean-derived salts is below 0.5 ppt.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>15 Palustrine Emergent Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all non-tidal wetlands dominated by persistent emergents, emergent mosses, or lichens, and all such wetlands that occur in tidal areas in which salinity due to ocean-derived salts is below 0.5 ppt.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>16 Estuarine Forest Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all tidal wetlands dominated by woody vegetation greater than or equal to 5 meters in height, and all such wetlands that occur in tidal areas in which salinity due to ocean-derived salts is above 0.5 parts per thousand (ppt).</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>17 Estuarine Scrub/Shrub Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all tidal wetlands dominated by woody vegetation less than or equal to 5 meters in height, and all such wetlands that occur in tidal areas in which salinity due to ocean-derived salts is above 0.5 ppt.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>18 Estuarine Emergent Wetland</edomv>
<edomvd>Characterized by erect, rooted, herbaceous hydrophytes (excluding mosses and lichens) that are present for most of the growing season in most years. Perennial plants usually dominate these wetlands. All water regimes are included except those that are subtidal and irregularly exposed.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>19 Unconsolidated Shore</edomv>
<edomvd>Characterized by substrates lacking vegetation except for pioneering plants that become established during brief periods when growing conditions are favorable. Erosion and deposition by waves and currents produce a number of landforms, such as beaches, bars, and flats, all of which are included in this class.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>20 Bare Land</edomv>
<edomvd>Composed of bare soil, rock, sand, silt, gravel, or other earthen material with little or no vegetation.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>21 Open Water</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes all areas of open water with less than 25 percent cover of vegetation or soil.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>22 Palustrine Aquatic Bed</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes wetlands and deepwater habitats dominated by plants that grow principally on or below the surface of the water for most of the growing season in most years. Salinity due to ocean-derived salts is below 0.5 ppt.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>23 Estuarine Aquatic Bed</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes widespread and diverse Algal Beds in the Marine and Estuarine Systems, where they occupy substrates characterized by a wide range of sediment depths and textures. They occur in both the Subtidal and Intertidal Subsystems and may grow to depths of 30 m (98 feet). This includes kelp forests. Salinity due to ocean-derived salts is equal to or above 0.5 ppt.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>24 Tundra</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes treeless cover beyond the latitudinal limit of the boreal forest in pole-ward regions and above the elevation range of the boreal forest in high mountains.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>25 Snow/Ice</edomv>
<edomvd>Includes persistent snow and ice that persist for greater portions of the year.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Dobson, J. et al, NOAA Coastal Change Analysis Program (C-CAP): Guidance for Regional Implementation, NOAA Technical Report NMFS 123, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1995.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>NOAA Coastal Services Center</cntorg>
<cntper>Clearinghouse Manager</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Clearinghouse Manager</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>2234 South Hobson Avenue</address>
<city>Charleston</city>
<state>SC</state>
<postal>29405-2413</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(843)740-1210</cntvoice>
<cntfax>(843)740-1224</cntfax>
<cntemail>clearinghouse@noaa.gov</cntemail>
<hours>Monday-Friday, 8-5 EST</hours>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
<distliab>Users must assume responsibility to determine the usability of these data.</distliab>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>ERDAS Imagine image file (.img)</formname>
</digtinfo>
<digtopt>
<offoptn>
<offmedia>CD-ROM</offmedia>
<recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
<compat>
ISO 9660 format allows the CD-ROM
to be read by most computer operating systems.
</compat>
</offoptn>
</digtopt>
</digform>
<fees>none</fees>
</stdorder>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20130904</metd>
<metrd>20130904</metrd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>NOAA Coastal Services Center</cntorg>
<cntper>Metadata Specialist</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Metadata Specialist</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>2234 S Hobson Ave.</address>
<city>Charleston</city>
<state>SC</state>
<postal>29405</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>843-740-1210</cntvoice>
<cntfax>843-740-1224</cntfax>
<cntemail>csc@noaa.gov</cntemail>
<hours>8:00 am to 5:00 pm EST.</hours>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC (Federal Geographic Data Committee) CSDGM (Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata)</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
