<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA) and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS).</origin>
				<pubdate>2012</pubdate>
				<title>National Hydrography Dataset Plus - NHDPlus</title>
				<edition>2.10</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data, raster digital data, tabular digital data</geoform>
				<onlink>http://www.epa.gov/waters</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>This high-level metadata data document will be supplemented with detailed regional metadata at a later date.

      The NHDPlusV2 is an integrated suite of application-ready geospatial data sets that incorporate many of the best features of the National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) and the National Elevation Dataset (NED). Interest in estimating stream flow volume and velocity to support pollutant fate-and-transport modeling was the driver behind the joint USEPA and USGS effort to develop the initial NHDPlus, referenced in this document as NHDPlusV1. NHDPlusV1 has been used in a wide variety of applications since its initial release in the fall of 2006. This widespread positive response prompted the multi-agency NHDPlus team to develop NHDPlus Version 2 (NHDPlusV2). The NHDPlusV2 includes a stream network (based on the 1:100,000-scale NHD), improved networking, naming, and "value-added attributes" (VAA's). NHDPlusV2 also includes elevation-derived catchments (drainage areas) produced using a drainage enforcement technique first broadly applied in New England, and thus dubbed "The New-England Method". This technique involves "burning-in" the 1:100,000-scale NHD and building "walls" using the national Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD). The hydro-enforced digital elevation model (DEM) is used to produce hydrologic derivatives that agree with the NHD and WBD. An interdisciplinary team from the USGS, USEPA and contractors, has found this method to produce the best quality NHD catchments using an automated process. 
      The VAAs include greatly enhanced capabilities for upstream and downstream navigation, analysis and modeling. Examples include: retrieve all flowlines (predominantly confluence-to-confluence stream segments) and catchments upstream of a given flowline using queries rather than by slower flowline-by-flowline navigation; retrieve flowlines by stream order; select a stream level path sorted in hydrologic order for stream profile mapping, analysis and plotting; and, calculate cumulative catchment attributes using streamlined VAA hydrologic sequencing routing attributes. 
      The VAAs include results from the use of these cumulative routing techniques, including cumulative drainage areas, precipitation, temperature, and runoff distributions. Several of these cumulative attributes are used to estimate mean annual flow and velocity as part of the VAAs. 
      NHDPlusV2 contains a snapshot (2012) of the 1:100,000-scale NHD that has been extensively improved over the snapshot used in NHDPlusV1. While these updates will eventually be stored in the central NHD repository at USGS, this will not be accomplished prior to distribution of NHDPlusV2. NHDPlusV2 users may not make updates to the NHD portions of NHDPlusV2 with the intent of sending these updates back to the USGS.  Updates to the 1:100,000-scale NHD snapshot in NHDPlusV2 should be sent to the USEPA as the primary steward.
    Purpose:
      The geospatial data sets included in NHDPlusV2 are intended to support a variety of water-related applications. They already have been used in an application to develop estimates of mean annual streamflow and velocity for each NHDFlowline feature in the conterminous United States. The results of these analyses are included with the NHDPlusV2 data. 
	NHDPlusV2 serves as the sample frame for the stream and lake surveys conducted by the USEPA under the National Aquatic Resources Surveys program.
      A water-quality model developed by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) called SPARROW (Spatially Referenced Regressions on Watershed Attributes), can utilizes the NHDPlusV2 network functionality to track the downstream transport of nutrients, sediments, or other substances. NHDPlusV2 water bodies and estimates of streamflow and velocity are used in SPARROW to identify reservoir retention and in-stream loss factors. NHDPlusV2 climatic and land surface attributes can be used in SPARROW to identify potential factors in the delivery of nutrients from the land surface to streams.
      NHDPlusV2 data is also being used in select areas for a USGS Web-based application, called StreamStats. StreamStats provides tools to interactively select any point in the implemented areas, delineate watersheds, and to obtain streamflow and watershed characteristics for the selected point. 
      NHDPlusV2 has been designed to accommodate many users' needs for future applications. NHDPlusV2 provides the framework and tools necessary to customize the behavior of the network relationships as well as building upon the attribute database, for which the user can assign their own data to the network.
</abstract>
			<purpose>The geospatial data sets included in NHDPlusV2 are intended to support a variety of water-related applications. They already have been used in an application to develop estimates of mean annual streamflow and velocity for each NHDFlowline feature in the conterminous United States. The results of these analyses are included with the NHDPlusV2 data. 
A water-quality model developed by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) called SPARROW (Spatially Referenced Regressions on Watershed Attributes), can utilize the NHDPlusV2 network functionality to track the downstream transport of nutrients, sediments, or other substances. NHDPlusV2 water bodies and estimates of streamflow and velocity are used in SPARROW to identify reservoir retention and in-stream loss factors. NHDPlusV2 climatic and land surface attributes can be used in SPARROW to identify potential factors in the delivery of nutrients from the land surface to streams.
NHDPlusV2 data is also being used in select areas for a USGS Web-based application, called StreamStats. StreamStats provides tools to interactively select any point in the implemented areas, delineate watersheds, and to obtain streamflow and watershed characteristics for the selected point. 
NHDPlusV2 has been designed to accommodate many users' needs for future applications. NHDPlusV2 provides the framework and tools necessary to customize the behavior of the network relationships as well as building upon the attribute database, for which the user can assign their own data to the network.</purpose>
			<supplinf>For more information, refer to the NHDPlusV2 Users Guide.</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>2012</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Irregular</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-125</westbc>
				<eastbc>
-66.5</eastbc>
				<northbc>
49.5</northbc>
				<southbc>
24.5</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>none</themekt>
				<themekey>Stream / River</themekey>
				<themekey>Lake / Pond</themekey>
				<themekey>Canal / Ditch</themekey>
				<themekey>Reservoir</themekey>
				<themekey>Spring / Seep</themekey>
				<themekey>Swamp / Marsh</themekey>
				<themekey>Artificial Path</themekey>
				<themekey>Reach</themekey>
				<themekey>Watershed</themekey>
				<themekey>Catchment</themekey>
				<themekey>EARTH SCIENCE</themekey>
				<themekey>Land Surface</themekey>
				<themekey>Topography</themekey>
				<themekey>Cartography</themekey>
				<themekey>GEODATA</themekey>
				<themekey>GIS</themekey>
				<themekey>USGS</themekey>
				<themekey>EPA</themekey>
				<themekey>Elevation</themekey>
				<themekey>National Elevation Dataset</themekey>
				<themekey>NED</themekey>
				<themekey>National Hydrography Dataset</themekey>
				<themekey>NHD</themekey>
				<themekey>NHDPlus</themekey>
				<themekey>Stream flow</themekey>
				<themekey>Stream velocity</themekey>
				<themekey>Spatially Referenced Regressions on Watershed Attributes</themekey>
				<themekey>SPARROW</themekey>
				<themekey>StreamStats</themekey>
				<themekey>Water-quality</themekey>
				<themekey>Hydrologic modeling</themekey>
				<themekey>River Coding Systems</themekey>
				<themekey>Hydrography</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>none</placekt>
				<placekey>United States of America</placekey>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
				<placekey>USA</placekey>
				<placekey>Alabama</placekey>
				<placekey>Arizona</placekey>
				<placekey>Arkansas</placekey>
				<placekey>California</placekey>
				<placekey>Colorado</placekey>
				<placekey>Connecticut</placekey>
				<placekey>Delaware</placekey>
				<placekey>District of Columbia</placekey>
				<placekey>Florida</placekey>
				<placekey>Georgia</placekey>
				<placekey>Idaho</placekey>
				<placekey>Illinois</placekey>
				<placekey>Indiana</placekey>
				<placekey>Iowa</placekey>
				<placekey>Kansas</placekey>
				<placekey>Kentucky</placekey>
				<placekey>Louisiana</placekey>
				<placekey>Maine</placekey>
				<placekey>Maryland</placekey>
				<placekey>Massachusetts</placekey>
				<placekey>Michigan</placekey>
				<placekey>Minnesota</placekey>
				<placekey>Mississippi</placekey>
				<placekey>Missouri</placekey>
				<placekey>Montana</placekey>
				<placekey>Nebraska</placekey>
				<placekey>Nevada</placekey>
				<placekey>New Hampshire</placekey>
				<placekey>New Jersey</placekey>
				<placekey>New Mexico</placekey>
				<placekey>New York</placekey>
				<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>North Dakota</placekey>
				<placekey>Ohio</placekey>
				<placekey>Oklahoma</placekey>
				<placekey>Oregon</placekey>
				<placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
				<placekey>Rhode Island</placekey>
				<placekey>South Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>South Dakota</placekey>
				<placekey>Tennessee</placekey>
				<placekey>Texas</placekey>
				<placekey>Utah</placekey>
				<placekey>Vermont</placekey>
				<placekey>Virginia</placekey>
				<placekey>Washington</placekey>
				<placekey>West Virginia</placekey>
				<placekey>Wisconsin</placekey>
				<placekey>Wyoming</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None.</accconst>
		<useconst>None.</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>see email address</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>D.C.</state>
					<postal>20460</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>see email address</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>waters_support@epa.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<datacred>Acknowledgement of the originating agencies (USEPA and USGS) would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</datacred>
		<native>Microsoft Windows Version 7.0; ESRI ArcGIS 9.3.1</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<logic>Data were processed with ArcGIS 9.3.1, and should not contain any topological errors.</logic>
		<complete>Data are complete for the conterminous United States. See release notes by Vector Processing Unit (VPU) for additional information.</complete>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) and the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA)</origin>
						<pubdate>2012</pubdate>
						<title>National Hydrography Dataset  (NHD) Medium Resolution</title>
						<edition>none</edition>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<onlink>http://nhd.usgs.gov</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>100000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>2012</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>The source NHD is a snapshot of the dataset accessed on 4/30/2010 and subsequently updated from 2010 to 2012.</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>NHD</srccitea>
				<srccontr>A snapshot of the NHD was used as the baseline framework from which enhancements to the network were built upon. Enhancements include feature names, network connectivity and network flow relationships. This enhanced NHD version was then used in conjunction with the NED, and WBD to create a hydro-enforced DEM, for generation of the catchment Grid/shapefile, and flow direction/accumulation Grids. The enhanced NHD was used to compute and assign flowline Value Added Attributes (VAAs) to this network.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), Denver</origin>
						<pubdate>2011</pubdate>
						<title>National Elevation Dataset  (NED)</title>
						<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>Multiple snapshots of the NED were obtained and used during NHDPlusV2 production. See the snapshot dates for each NHDPlusV2 Vector Processing Unit (VPU) in this Source Citation.</othercit>
						<onlink>http://ned.usgs.gov/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>disc</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<mdattim>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>201008</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>201102</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>201106</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>201108</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>201112</caldate>
							</sngdate>
						</mdattim>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication dates</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>NED</srccitea>
				<srccontr>NED data used in combination with NHD and WBD to create a hydro-enforced, NHDPlusV2 Catchments, surface flow direction and accumulation Grids. Stream elevations from NED which were used to help derive stream slope and stream velocity. NED snapshot dates used were as follows: 
August 2010 - VPU04
February 2011 - VPUs 05, 06
June 2011 - VPU 17
August 2011 - VPUs 07, 10L, 10U, 11, 18
December 2011 - VPUs 01, 02, 03N, 03S, 03W, 08, 09, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</origin>
						<pubdate>2012</pubdate>
						<title>Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD)</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<othercit>Multiple snapshots of the WBD were obtained and used during NHDPlusV2 production. See the snapshot dates for each NHDPlusV2 Vector Processing Unit (VPU) in this Source Citation.</othercit>
						<onlink>http://www.nrcs.usda.gov/wps/portal/nrcs/main/national/water/watersheds/dataset</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<mdattim>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20100831</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20110310</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20110714</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20110916</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20111007</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20111114</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20111202</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20111221</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20120201</caldate>
							</sngdate>
						</mdattim>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication dates</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>WBD</srccitea>
				<srccontr>12-digit Hydrologic Unit (HUC 12) divides from the Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD) were used as ridgeline enforcment input in a process called "walling" in the production of hydro-enforced DEMs. Closed basin designations, from the HUC 12 polygon data were used to impose "sinks" in the hydro-enforced DEMs.  These DEMs are the source data from which NHDPlusV2 Catchments are delineated from. Catchments with corresponding boundaries in the WBD generally agree with the WBD to within one or two 30-m grid cells. Some larger differences between catchment boundaries and WBD boundaries do exist, however. NHDPlusV2 Flow Direction and Accumulation Grids are hydrologic derivative products of the hydro-enforced DEMs. 

Dates of WBD snapshots used were as follows: 
August 31, 2010 - VPU 04
March 10, 2011 - VPUs  05, 06
July 14, 2011 - VPU 17
September 16, 2011 - VPU 10L
October 7, 2011 - VPU 10U
November 14, 2011 - VPUs 07, 11
December 2, 2011- VPU 18
December 21, 2011 - VPUs 09, 12
February 1, 2012 - VPUs 01, 02, 03N, 03S, 03W,  08,  13,  14, 15,  16

The February 1, 2012 WBD snapshot used to migrate NHD medium resolution Reachcode assignment to agree with WBD HUC 8 codes.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>David W. Stewart, Alan Rea and David M. Wolock</origin>
						<pubdate>200604</pubdate>
						<title>USGS Streamgages Linked to the Medium Resolution NHD</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Data Series</sername>
							<issue>DS-195</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, Va</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://water.usgs.gov/lookup/getspatial?streamgages</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>2006</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>DS195</srccitea>
				<srccontr>The gage locations, which were spatially referenced to the NHDPlusV1 flowlines, were migrated to NHDPlusV2 flowlines and stored in the NHDPlusV2 Gageloc feature class.  The Gageloc feature class was used for the QAQC of the estimates of mean annual stream flow and also in a gage flow adjustment process applied to the final mean annual stream flow estimates.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>David W. Stewart</origin>
						<pubdate>201102</pubdate>
						<title>Written communication:  4,446  Updated or Additional Records for Source Titled "USGS Streamgages Linked to the Medium Resolution NHD"</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<onlink>none</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>electronic mail system</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>201102</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>Stewart, 2011, written communication</srccitea>
				<srccontr>The 4,446 updates were applied to the NHDPlusV2 Gageloc feature class.  The Gageloc feature class was used for the QAQC of the estimates of mean annual stream flow and also in a gage flow adjustment process applied to the final mean annual stream flow estimates.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>D:\refresh\documentation\metadata\NHDPlus17\metadata.xml</srcused>
				<procdate>20120608</procdate>
				<proctime>11592000</proctime>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>not available, see email address</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>D.C.</state>
					<postal>20460</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>not available, see email address</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>waters_support@epa.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>Although this data set has been used by the U.S. Government, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the U.S. Government as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the U.S. Government in the use of this data, software, or 
related materials.
 
Any use of trade, product, or firm names is for descriptive purposes only and does not imply endorsement by the U.S. Government.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>ESRI Workspace</formname>
					<filedec>.7z</filedec>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>http://www.epa.gov/waters</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
						<accinstr>http://www.epa.gov/waters</accinstr>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>none</fees>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20120611</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>not available, see email address</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>D.C.</state>
					<postal>20460</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>not available, see email address</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>waters_support@epa.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
	</metainfo>
	<Esri><ModDate>20120619</ModDate><ModTime>12135600</ModTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20120614</mdDateSt></metadata>
