<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Shoreline Classification (one can symbolize on hardened)</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>file://\\Bishop\nas1\MRGIS_shapefiles\2010_08_04current\esi_albers\esi_classification_fl_arc\esi_classification_fl_arc.shp</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This GIS data set comprises an update to the shoreline habitat component of the Environmental Sensitivity Index (ESI) and Gulf-Wide Information System (G-WIS) databases for the coastal zone of Florida, including the lower St. Johns River. The ESI and G-WIS data suites characterize coastal habitats and resources for environmental planning and natural resource management purposes, including oil spill planning and response. The ESI and G-WIS data include three main components: shoreline habitats, sensitive biological resources, and human-use resources. The data layer described in this document contains the linear ESI (complete chains) shoreline habitat classification. See also the separate ESIP (GT-polygon) layer for polygonal ESI habitat features. The attribute table for these data has been expanded to include an easier to interpret ESI shoreline description and classification system for use in the Florida Marine Spill Analysis System (FMSAS) map legends and products. The original DESC (Detailed shoreline classification verbal description) field has been simplified into the SHRTDESC field (shorter verbal description) in order to fit into the textual "Resources At Risk" report generated by the FMSAS. Additional fields have been added to the attribute table to simplify map symbology and maximize understanding of habitat types for protection by responders. These fields are MOST_SENS (Classification of the most sensitive shoreline type (to oil spills) on any particular arc), and MSTSENDES (Verbal description of the most sensitive shoreline type). A frequency of each arc ESI classification (complex classification) was also generated in this process (FREQUENCY). See Supplemental Information for examples of this process. Richard Knudsen - FMSAS Manager, April 2004John Knowles received from Alison Higgins of the The Nature Conservancy by email on April 4, 2011 who received from below: Manny CelaProgram Area ManagerSouth Florida Regional Planning Council(954)985-4416/(800)985-4416</abstract>
      <purpose>The ESI and G-WIS data provide sensitive areas data for oil spill planning and response and other environmental management and natural resource purposes.  The Clean Water Act with amendments by the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 requires response plans for immediate and effective protection of sensitive areas. These data also support other related state and federal regulatory requirements for oil spill prevention, planning, response, and restoration.

Anything with shoreline type code 1B and 8B will be good for hardened manmade shoreline.  </purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-81.815767</westbc>
        <eastbc>-80.168590</eastbc>
        <northbc>25.543351</northbc>
        <southbc>24.544002</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords />
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The ESI and G-WIS databases were developed to provide summary information on sensitive natural and human-use resources for the purposes of oil spill planning, environmental planning, and natural resource management.  Although the ESI and G-WIS data should be a valuable planning and resource management tool, they should not be used to the exclusion of other pertinent data or information held by state or federal agencies or other organizations.  Likewise, these data cannot be used in place of consultations with environmental, natural resource, and cultural resource agencies, or in place of field surveys.  Also, these data and any related map products should not be used for navigation.
Recognize that the information contained in the ESI and G-WIS databases represents known concentration areas or occurrences of natural, cultural, and human-use resources, but does not necessarily represent the full distribution or range of each species or resource.  This is particularly important to recognize when considering potential impacts to protected resources, such as endangered species, wetlands, archaeological sites, etc.
For more information or guidance on proper and improper uses of these data, please contact the Florida Marine Research Institute (FMRI) and Research Planning, Inc.  Acknowledgement of the publishers, contributors, and sources listed in the Data_Set_Credit (below) and Lineage section of this document would be appreciated in products derived from or utilizing these data.
Acknowledgement of the FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute) as the data source would be appreciated in any products developed from these data, and such acknowledgment as is standard for citation and legal practices for data source is expected by users of this data.  Please cite the original metadata when using portions of the record to create a similar record of slightly altered data, such as reprojection. If any data are modified or adjusted, please share the edited information with FWC. Users should be aware that comparison with other data sets for the same area from other time periods may be inaccurate due to inconsistencies resulting from changes in mapping conventions, data collection, and computer processes over time. FWC shall not be liable for improper or incorrect use of this data. These data are not legal documents and are not to be used as such.  This is not a survey data set and should not be utilized as such. These data are not to be used for navigation.

http://ocean.floridamarine.org/mrgis/Description_Layers_Marine.htm#benthic 
</useconst>
    <datacred>This project was supported by the Florida Marine Research Institute (FMRI), Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission (FFWCC).  Tara Morgan with FMRI's Coastal and Marine Resource Assessment (CAMRA) program served as contract and technical manager for the project.  Henry Norris, Kathleen O'Keife, William Sargent and other CAMRA staff contributed significantly to the project, as did many other FMRI staff and individuals from several state and federal agencies and other organizations. At Research Planning, Inc. (RPI), Lee Diveley, Colin Plank, Zach Nixon, Jeffrey Dahlin, Jessica Dimmler, Jon Whitlock, Katie Born, Erin Rieber, Heidi Hinkeldey, Chris Locke, Mark White and Scott Zengel contributed to the project. Vermell Pyatt prepared the final metadata.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>3030</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]-20037700-30241100148923141.92838538-10000010000-100000100000.0010.0010.001true3857</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000006714873101998366</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000006714873101998366</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>FMRI.esi_classification_fl_arc</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The data layer ESI contains arcs (complete chains) representing the shoreline attributed with a habitat and oil spill sensitivity classification system described in NOAA (2002), Environmental Sensitivity Index Guidelines, Version 3.0, NOAA Technical Memorandum NOS OR&amp;R 11, Seattle, Wa., 89 pp + appendices.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Research Planning, Inc.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>G_SOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Geographic source integer identifier that links records in ESI.AAT to records in the SOURCES data table.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>N</rdommax>
          </rdom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LINE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of geographic feature</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>S</edomv>
            <edomvd>Shoreline</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>M</edomv>
            <edomvd>Marsh</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>H</edomv>
            <edomvd>Hydrography</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Breakwater</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MANGROVE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Refers to whether the arc is a mangrove</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y</edomv>
            <edomvd>Yes</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>No</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MOST_SENS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>ESI code representing the most sensitive habitat type present for a given segment of shoreline. This is biased towards alphabetical order for segments where two habitats of equal sensitivity are present. For example, for an ESI of 10A/10B, the MOST_SENS value is 10A.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Leng</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MSTSENDES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Textual description of the most sensitive habitat type.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHRT_DESC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A textual description of all shoreline types represented by the arc.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VER_DATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date of field verification</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Numeric</edomv>
            <edomvd>MMYYYY</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VER_NEED</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Refers to whether field verification is needed</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y</edomv>
            <edomvd>Yes</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>No</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>A_SOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Attribute source integer identifier that links records in ESI.AAT to records in the SOURCES data table.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>N</rdommax>
          </rdom>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CASE_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>ESI numerical/alpha value of the most oil spill sensitive shoreline type for any given arc regardless of landward or seaward orientation.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FMRI Staff</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrvai>
          <attrvae>Used for symbology and quick analysis</attrvae>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DESC_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Frequency of arcs with a given ESI value (complex)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>summary tables</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Desc_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field contains a description of the ESI code.  Some items in this field may be abbreviated, such as: Est = Estuarine, Lac = Lacustrine, and Riv = Riverine.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FMRI staff added this field.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Envir</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Regional environment</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>E</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>L</edomv>
            <edomvd>Lacustrine</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>R</edomv>
            <edomvd>Riverine</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
        <begdatea>1996</begdatea>
        <enddatea>2001</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ESI</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The item ESI contains values representing the ESI shoreline type (shoreline habitat type).  In many cases shorelines are ranked with multiple codes such as 6B/3A (listed landward to seaward from left to right).  The first number is the most landward shoreline type, riprap, with fine- to medium-grained sand beaches being the shoreline type closest to the water.  Singular shoreline types are listed below.  No multiple codes are listed, but all multiple codes included in the data set can be assembled from the codes described.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine: Exposed rocky shores; Riverine: Exposed rocky banks</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Exposed, solid man-made structures</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Exposed wave-cut platforms in bedrock, mud, or clay; Lacustrine: Shelving bedrock shores; Riverine: Rocky shoals, bedrock ledges</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Exposed scarps and steep slopes in clay</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Fine- to medium- grained sand beaches</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Scarps and steep slopes in sand; Lacustrine: Eroding scarps in unconsolidated sediments; Riverine: Exposed, eroding banks in unconsolidated sediments</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3C</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Tundra cliffs</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>4</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Course-grained sand beaches; Lacustrine: Sand beaches; Riverine: Sandy bars and gently sloping banks</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>5</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine: Mixed sand and gravel beaches; Riverine: Mixed sand and gravel bars and gently sloping banks</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>6A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine: Gravel beaches; Riverine: Gravel bars and gently sloping banks</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>6B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Riprap</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>7</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine: Exposed tidal flats</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine: Sheltered scarps in bedrock, mud, or clay</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Sheltered solid man-made structures</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8C</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Sheltered riprap</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8D</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Sheltered rocky rubble shores</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8E</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Peat shorelines</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8F</edomv>
            <edomvd>Riverine: Vegetated, steeply-sloping bluffs</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>9A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Sheltered tidal flats; Lacustrine: Sheltered sand/mud flats</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>9B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Sheltered, vegetated low banks</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>9C</edomv>
            <edomvd>Hypersaline tidal flats</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10A</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine: Salt- and brackish- water marsh</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Freshwater marsh</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10C</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverine: Swamps</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10D</edomv>
            <edomvd>Estuarine/Lacustrine/Riverince: Scrub-shrub wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1C</edomv>
            <edomvd>Exposed rocky cliffs with boulder talus base</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Research Planning, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FREQUENCY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Verbal short description of most oil spill sensitive shoreline type</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FMRI Staff</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrvai>
          <attrvae>Verbal description of both ESI code and shoreline description, Used for symbology and quick analysis</attrvae>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20120412</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>