<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Exposure Sub-Index</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This sub-index is made up of 5 variables: Critical Facilities Exposure, Road Exposure, Building Exposure, Livelihood Exposure, and Community Exposure. All of these variables were calculated for each enumeration district and used to create an Exposure Sub-Index. A description of how each field was calculated can be found in the Field and Subtypes part of the metadata.</abstract><purpose>A suite of variables that describes the degree to which a community experiences inundation (i.e., flooding) by a given scenario. We focused our Exposure Sub-index calculations on inundation from storm scenarios with possible sea level rise. This information will help inform the Socioeconomic Vulnerability Assessment under the Nature Conservancy's AWE Project.

Scientists around the world agree that climate change is indisputable.  Impacts, including rising sea levels, increased storm intensity, warming temperatures and acidifying waters, dying coral reefs, shifting fish stocks, and incidence of flooding and drought, are already being felt, and are expected to continue and increase for decades to come. 

Nature holds some of the world’s best and most practical solutions to climate change, solutions that keep nature and people healthy, safe, and secure. The goal of At the Water’s Edge (AWE) is to demonstrate that governments and people in vulnerable coastal communities in Grenada and St. Vincent &amp; the Grenadines (SVG) can enhance their resilience to climate change by protecting, restoring and effectively managing their marine and coastal ecosystems (also known as ecosystem-based adaptation or EBA) and strengthening local capacity for adaptation.</purpose></descript><spdom><bounding><westbc>-61.802482</westbc><eastbc>-61.378025</eastbc><northbc>12.531896</northbc><southbc>11.982904</southbc></bounding></spdom><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>GIS Data User AgreementAny Geographic Information System (GIS) data or information received from The Nature Conservancy (TNC) or downloaded from a TNC site (collectively “GIS Data”) is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). More specific limitations of this data are stated below. By using this information, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and accepted the terms and conditions stated in this GIS Data User Agreement. TNC reserves the right to change this Agreement at any time and without notice. Your use of this information shall constitute your agreement to be bound by this Agreement and any changes.The user hereby acknowledges that the GIS Data is subject to constant change and that its accuracy, including but not limited to, its accuracy as to labeling, dimensions, boundaries, placement or location of any map features therein, cannot be guaranteed. All GIS Data is provided as is, with potential faults, errors and without warranty of any kind, expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. Additionally, TNC does not warrant that the information contained in this GIS Data will meet the user's requirements or that the operation of the GIS Data will be uninterrupted or error free, or that data defects will be corrected. The entire risk as to the quality, performance and usefulness of the GIS Data rests with the user.The user, in using this GIS Data, hereby releases TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors or employees from any and all claims, actions, or causes of action for damages including, but not limited to, any costs of recovering, reprogramming or reproducing any programs or data stored in or used with the GIS Data, damage to property, damages for personal injury or for any lost profits, lost savings, or other special, incidental or consequential damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the GIS Data, even if such parties have been advised of the possibility of such damage. User agrees to indemnify and hold harmless TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors and employees from any and all liability claims or damages to any person or property arising from or connected with the use of the GIS Data.Further Data RestrictionsUse of the GIS Data is limited to academic or scientific purposes and may not be used for profitable purposes or by a for-profit corporation. The user hereby commits to acknowledge The Nature Conservancy as the data source and compiler when GIS Data received from TNC (through formal delivery or from a website) is used in the preparation of reports, papers, publications, maps and any other products. Any use, display or incorporation of GIS Data shall include the date on which such information was provided.The user also agrees to provide TNC, at no cost to TNC, a digital copy of any Geo-Spatial Data, tabular data, reports, imagery, drawing(s), plan(s), and any other form of result that were derived directly or indirectly from the use of these data provided by TNC along with its associated metadata.To ensure that appropriate documentation and data limitations are provided, downloaded data should not be redistributed to third-party users or uploaded to a central server unless written permission is granted by the TNC’s Caribbean Program GIS data manager (caribgis@tnc.org) and Caribbean Program Director (Philip Kramer: pkramer@tnc.org).When such GIS Data is used the following disclaimer and waiver of liability shall be included and displayed prominently so as to alert any person viewing or utilizing this information:NOTICE: It is understood that, while The Nature Conservancy and its partners of information have no indication or reason to believe that there are inaccuracies or defects in information incorporated in the base map, The Nature Conservancy and its data partners make NO REPRESENTATIONS OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE, NOR ARE ANY SUCH WARRANTIES TO BE IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THE INFORMATION OR DATA, FURNISHED HEREIN.</useconst><datacred>Created by The Nature Conservancy (2014) caribgis@tnc.org</datacred><native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.1.3497</native></idinfo><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>287</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><mapproj><mapprojn>WGS 1984 UTM Zone 20N</mapprojn><transmer><sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer><longcm>-63.0</longcm><latprjo>0.0</latprjo><feast>500000.0</feast><fnorth>0.0</fnorth></transmer></mapproj><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres><ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres></coordrep><plandu>meter</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn><ellips>WGS 1984</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257223563</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>grd_moot_Exposure_2011</enttypl></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>FID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PNAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Parish Name</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>T_CTRY1</attrlabl><attrdef>3 letter country identifier</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>T_CTRY2</attrlabl><attrdef>4 digit country identifier, same as calling code</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>PCODE</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique 2 digit parish identifier</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ED_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>3-4 digit ED identifier from 2011 census</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ED_KEY</attrlabl><attrdef>5-6 digit ED code consisting of 2 digit unique parish identifier and the 3-4 digit ED_ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>KEY</attrlabl><attrdef>6 digit ED code consisting of 2 digit unique parish identifier and 4 digit parish code (creating using ED_ID and adding a zero to create 4 digit number where necessary)</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>T_ED</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique ED identifier consisting of 4 digit country code, and 6 digit Key</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREASQM</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of enumeration district in meters</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREASQKM</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of enumeration district in kilometers</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREASQMI</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of enumeration district miles</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ROADMI</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road per ED</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>BAREASQFT</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of building footprints</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>CIFCOUNT</attrlabl><attrdef>Number of all the critical infrastructure and facilities located within an ED (airports, bus stations, ferry locations, ports, sewage stations, water treatment plants, cell towers, electrical plants, fire stations, medical facilities, police stations, hurricane shelters). </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>CLFCOUNT</attrlabl><attrdef>Number of livelihood facilities located within an ED (landing sites, fish markets, ship-building, gear storage facilities, hotels, dive shops). </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>CMFCOUNT</attrlabl><attrdef>Number of community facilities located within an ED (schools, religious centers, financial institutes, cemeteries). </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRI_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated by 100 year Flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRIP_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated divided by total length of road. </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAI_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated by 100 year Flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAIP_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated divided by total number of buildings</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFI_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated by 100 year Flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFP_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated divided by total number of Critical Infrastructure and Facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFI_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated by 100 year Flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFP_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated divided by total number of fisheries facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFI_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated by 100 year Flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFP_100</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated divided by total number of community facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_100</attrlabl><attrdef>The final average of the 5 percentages for exposure (roads, buildings, critical facilities, livelihood facilities, and community facilities) for 100 year flood</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRI_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated by Hurricane Lenny with no SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRIP_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated divided by total length of road. </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAI_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated by Hurricane Lenny with no SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAIP_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated divided by total number of buildings</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFI_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated by Hurricane Lenny with no SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFP_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated divided by total number of Critical Infrastructure and Facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFI_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated by Hurricane Lenny with no SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFP_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated divided by total number of fisheries facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFI_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated by Hurricane Lenny with no SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFP_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated divided by total number of community facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>The final average of the 5 percentages for exposure (roads, buildings, critical facilities, livelihood facilities, and community facilities) for Hurricane Lenny</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRI_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated by Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRIP_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated divided by total length of road. </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAI_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated by Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAIP_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated divided by total number of buildings</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFI_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated by Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFP_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated divided by total number of Critical Infrastructure and Facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFI_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated by Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFP_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated divided by total number of fisheries facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFI_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated by Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFP_L1</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated divided by total number of community facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LEN1SLR</attrlabl><attrdef>The final average of the 5 percentages for exposure (roads, buildings, critical facilities, livelihood facilities, and community facilities) for Hurricane Lenny with 1m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRI_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated by Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LRIP_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of road inundated divided by total length of road. </attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAI_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated by Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_BAIP_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of buildings inundated divided by total number of buildings</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFI_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated by Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CIFP_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Critical Infrastructure and Facilities inundated divided by total number of Critical Infrastructure and Facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFI_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated by Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CLFP_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Livelihood facilities inundated divided by total number of fisheries facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFI_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated by Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_CMFP_L2</attrlabl><attrdef>Community facilities inundated divided by total number of community facilities</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>E_LEN2SLR</attrlabl><attrdef>The final average of the 5 percentages for exposure (roads, buildings, critical facilities, livelihood facilities, and community facilities) for Hurricane Lenny with 2m SLR</attrdef></attr></detailed></eainfo><metainfo><metd>20141112</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo><dataIdInfo><idPurp>A suite of variables that describes the degree to which a community experiences inundation (i.e., flooding) by a given scenario. We focused our Exposure Sub-index calculations on inundation from storm scenarios with possible sea level rise. This information will help inform the Socioeconomic Vulnerability Assessment under the Nature Conservancy's AWE Project.

Scientists around the world agree that climate change is indisputable.  Impacts, including rising sea levels, increased storm intensity, warming temperatures and acidifying waters, dying coral reefs, shifting fish stocks, and incidence of flooding and drought, are already being felt, and are expected to continue and increase for decades to come. 

Nature holds some of the world’s best and most practical solutions to climate change, solutions that keep nature and people healthy, safe, and secure. The goal of At the Water’s Edge (AWE) is to demonstrate that governments and people in vulnerable coastal communities in Grenada and St. Vincent &amp; the Grenadines (SVG) can enhance their resilience to climate change by protecting, restoring and effectively managing their marine and coastal ecosystems (also known as ecosystem-based adaptation or EBA) and strengthening local capacity for adaptation.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This sub-index is made up of 5 variables: Critical Facilities Exposure, Road Exposure, Building Exposure, Livelihood Exposure, and Community Exposure. All of these variables were calculated for each enumeration district and used to create an Exposure Sub-Index. A description of how each field was calculated can be found in the Field and Subtypes part of the metadata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Created by The Nature Conservancy (2014) caribgis@tnc.org</idCredit><idCitation><resTitle>Exposure Sub-Index</resTitle></idCitation><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GIS Data User AgreementAny Geographic Information System (GIS) data or information received from The Nature Conservancy (TNC) or downloaded from a TNC site (collectively “GIS Data”) is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). More specific limitations of this data are stated below. By using this information, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and accepted the terms and conditions stated in this GIS Data User Agreement. TNC reserves the right to change this Agreement at any time and without notice. Your use of this information shall constitute your agreement to be bound by this Agreement and any changes.The user hereby acknowledges that the GIS Data is subject to constant change and that its accuracy, including but not limited to, its accuracy as to labeling, dimensions, boundaries, placement or location of any map features therein, cannot be guaranteed. All GIS Data is provided as is, with potential faults, errors and without warranty of any kind, expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. Additionally, TNC does not warrant that the information contained in this GIS Data will meet the user's requirements or that the operation of the GIS Data will be uninterrupted or error free, or that data defects will be corrected. The entire risk as to the quality, performance and usefulness of the GIS Data rests with the user.The user, in using this GIS Data, hereby releases TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors or employees from any and all claims, actions, or causes of action for damages including, but not limited to, any costs of recovering, reprogramming or reproducing any programs or data stored in or used with the GIS Data, damage to property, damages for personal injury or for any lost profits, lost savings, or other special, incidental or consequential damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the GIS Data, even if such parties have been advised of the possibility of such damage. User agrees to indemnify and hold harmless TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors and employees from any and all liability claims or damages to any person or property arising from or connected with the use of the GIS Data.Further Data RestrictionsUse of the GIS Data is limited to academic or scientific purposes and may not be used for profitable purposes or by a for-profit corporation. The user hereby commits to acknowledge The Nature Conservancy as the data source and compiler when GIS Data received from TNC (through formal delivery or from a website) is used in the preparation of reports, papers, publications, maps and any other products. Any use, display or incorporation of GIS Data shall include the date on which such information was provided.The user also agrees to provide TNC, at no cost to TNC, a digital copy of any Geo-Spatial Data, tabular data, reports, imagery, drawing(s), plan(s), and any other form of result that were derived directly or indirectly from the use of these data provided by TNC along with its associated metadata.To ensure that appropriate documentation and data limitations are provided, downloaded data should not be redistributed to third-party users or uploaded to a central server unless written permission is granted by the TNC’s Caribbean Program GIS data manager (caribgis@tnc.org) and Caribbean Program Director (Philip Kramer: pkramer@tnc.org).When such GIS Data is used the following disclaimer and waiver of liability shall be included and displayed prominently so as to alert any person viewing or utilizing this information:NOTICE: It is understood that, while The Nature Conservancy and its partners of information have no indication or reason to believe that there are inaccuracies or defects in information incorporated in the base map, The Nature Conservancy and its data partners make NO REPRESENTATIONS OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE, NOR ARE ANY SUCH WARRANTIES TO BE IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THE INFORMATION OR DATA, FURNISHED HEREIN.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><Esri><ModDate>20141112</ModDate><ModTime>5374800</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile><CreaDate>20141113</CreaDate><CreaTime>06271800</CreaTime><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\TERMINAL\D\temp\xml\gsvg_grd_moot_Exposure_2011</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="C:\Users\lynnetteroth\Desktop\Vulnerability Data\gsvg_grd_moot_Exposure_2011" dest="\\TERMINAL\D\temp\xml\gsvg_grd_moot_Exposure_2011" date="20141113" time="06271800"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv></metadata>
